Jasper Furniss

Front End Engineer

jasperfurniss@gmail.com

I've been solving problems my whole life and writing code since 2012.

I love building web applications, creative design, simple meaningful UX animations, every kind of front-end web development, websites that make sense, full-stack development, solving challenging problems, and accomplishing tasks through people.

Learning is my passion. If there is a new technology that solves problems in a more efficient way, I want to grasp it. I work hard to navigate problems and approach them with tact. I love to build front-end heavy web apps with Javascript, Less, Sass, and CSS3. At the same time, I'm familiar with Ruby and even messing around in databases, particularly PostgresSQL.

I really enjoy owning a product, guiding the process, building out the codebase and seeing it come to life. I get pumped when a designer throws me a .psd file and says, "Go build this." Moreover, I love to collaborate with designers to make a product come to life. On a normal day, I'll make daily pulls & pushes to gitlab, knock out tasks on Jira, read React.js docs, follow a tutorial to solve a unique problem, collaborate with a designer on a feature, and drink way too much coffee.

I'm available for freelance, contract, or full-time work and can help by using the following technologies & more:

- React + GraphQL
- Ruby on Rails
- Django & Python
- Ember.js
- Backbone.js & Underscore.js
- ES6, ES7
- HTML5, CSS3, Vanilla JS
- Pre-processors (Sass, Less)
- CSS-in-JS (JSS)

- AWS & Jenkins
- PostgresSQL, MySQL
- Cross-browser compatibility
- Browserstack, Ghost Inspector
- Git/Github/Gitlab
- Zeplin, Marvel
- Jira, Trello, Slack, Toggl
- JS libraries like Highcharts.js and D3.js

Experience

Software Engineer at Grace Hill

August 2017 - Present

At Grace Hill, I built a custom quiz builder in React.js for our entire company's LMS in the first two months of getting hired. I now work as a software engineer on our Ruby on Rails team to build out new features on our application called Vision. I make daily pushes to Gitlab, fix bugs, collaborate with our QA team, attend daily standups, code custom designs, and bring ideas to life in the code. Some of our stack includes: Git, Gitlab, Jenkins, Ruby on Rails, AWS (i've got experience deploying too.), JS, Vue, React, Slack, and lots of 3rd party API integrations.

Front End Developer at Milliken

June 2017 - August 2017 (3 months)

At Milliken, I use my eye for design to develop a UI for the engineering team in the carpet division. I helped build the foundation for their new multi-lingual Milliken Carpet site. I used ui frameworks like bootstrap and flexbox grid.

Software Developer at Worthwhile

September 2015 - January 2017 (1 year 5 months)

My main responsibility was to build large-scale web and mobile applications. At Worthwhile I was busy defining application architecture, giving input to our art director, coding the front-end dev work, and building the Django backend. I took client and team feedback to make my project awesome and shepherd it to production. I was responsible for implementing solutions for real-world business hurdles with Django and PostgreSQL, which meant wrestling with the problems of data storage and management. I was also responsible for crafting the HTML/CSS & JavaScript for the client-side, being well-versed in Bootstrap, LESS, jQuery, and React.js. Finally, I was able to draw wireframes, help estimate a few projects, and build a fluid system from wireframes.

The Iron Yard Digital Healthcare Accelerator: ThoroughCare, Inc.

April 2015 - July 2015 (4 months)

ThoroughCare is a digital healthcare company revolutionizing the way patient assessments are performed. ThoroughCare has created a standalone assessment tool which allows for increased patient engagement and more efficient assessments. ThoroughCare is designed to be integrated with 3rd party software as an "add-on" to give companies the option to have state-of-the art assessment tools with their product suite. After being chosen for the 2013 IronYard digital healthcare accelerator, ThoroughCare was officially launched. Being the front-end developer on this project was very exciting and I was able to collaborate with a team of Ruby devs to code the UI of this product.

Freelance Web Developer at Jasper Furniss Inc.

September 2014 - September 2015 (1 year 1 month)

Design incredible web applications so that passionate people can tell their story to the world. During this period, I jumped right in with clients and helped build web apps, websites, and executed full-stack web development for clients.

Worship Leader at Fellowship Greenville

April 2009 - September 2014 (5 years 6 months)

Work with creatives to design meaningful experiences
Shepherd people through musical worship
Train worship leaders
Equip called musicians to serve the church
Cast vision for student ministry

Worship Leader at Shannon Forest Presbyterian Church

September 2006 - April 2009 (2 years 8 months)

Craft experiences and build a creative team
Lead worship for the congregation
Lead student ministry worship for Middle School & High School

Education

The Iron Yard Academy

Front End Engineering, 2015

Team Treehouse

24 Courses, 2014 - 2016

Liberty University

Master of Arts (M.A.), Worship Studies w/ Specialization in Leadership, 2010 - 2014

North Greenville University

Bachelor of Arts (B.A.), Music & Theology, 2005 - 2008